Guide to the Dairymen's League records, 1915-1946.
Dairymen's League records, 1915-1946.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dairymen's League records, 1915-1946.
1820
John D. Miller
28 cubic ft.
Correspondence, briefs, printed case reports, speeches, articles, bulletins, press releases, newspaper clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Business papers, copies of speeches and articles, and other miscellaneous papers of Miller.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Agriculturist, lawyer.
Judge John D. Miller served as Vice President and General Counsel of the Dairymen's League.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Business papers of Miller include correspondence; briefs, printed case reports, and other legal papers; mimeographed and printed copies of speeches and articles by Miller and others; statistics, bulletins, press releases, newspaper clippings, and much other printed material; and miscellaneous papers. The papers pertain to accounting, finances, taxation on cooperatives, anti-trust laws, contracts, cost of milk production, economic conditions, marketing agreements, milk strikes, national defense, national political platforms and conventions, rural credit, tariffs, uniform milk ordinances, nitrates (Muscle Shoals, Alabama), Danish cooperatives; farm legislation, including the McFadden Rural Credit Bill, McNary Haugen Bill, and milk bonding legislation and other matters. Correspondents include Howard E. Babcock, E.M. Bailey, Ezra Taft Banson, Senator John J. Blaine, Homer L. Brinkley, Edward R. Eastman, D.N. Geyer, L.E. Griffing, Charles W. Holman, A.M. Loomis, H.C. McKenzie, C.O. Moser, William I. Myers, Frank A. Pearson, T.W. Phillips, Stanley Reed, Quentin Reynolds, Edward A. Rumely, Fred H. Sexauer, A.F. Spooner, W.A. Stocking, Jr., F.H. Thompson, Edward J. Tracy, Charles H. Tuck, Edward F. Vincent, and George F. Warren.
Papers also pertain to the Agricultural Adjustment Administration, Amercian Agriculturist, American Association of Creamery Butter Manufacturers, American Institute of Cooperation, Bank for Cooperatives (1935-41), Bureau of Raw Materials, Committee for the Nation, Co-operative Digest, Farm Credit Administration, Farmers Milk Producers Association, Federal Farm Board, Federal Tariff Commission, Federal Reserve System, Federal Trade Commission, Grange League Federation University, National Cooperative Council (1933-35), National Cooperative Milk Producers Federation (1922-28, 1930-34, 1940-46), National Council of Cooperative Associations, National Council of Farmers Cooperatives (1941-42), National Dairy Union, New York State College of Agriculture, New England Agricultural Conference, Southern Tariff Association, Temple of Agriculture, U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Industrial Conference Board, U.S. Dairy Association, World Dairy Conference, and many other organizations.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Miller, John D.; Babcock, Howard Edward, 1889-1950.; Bailey, E. M.; Benson, Ezra Taft.; Blaine, John James, 1875-1934.; Brinkley, Homer Lee, 1898-; Eastman, Edward Roe, 1885-1970.; Geyer, Don N.; Griffing, L. E.; Holman, Charles William, 1886-; Loomis, A. M.; McKenzie, H. C.; Moser, Christopher Otto, 1885-1935.; Myers, William Irving, 1891-1976.; Pearson, Frank A. (Frank Ashmore), 1887-; Phillips, Thomas Wharton, b. 1874.; Reed, Stanley Forman, 1884-1980.; Reynolds, Quentin James, 1902-1965.; Rumely, Edward (Edward Aloysius), 1882-; Sexauer, Fred Henry, 1891-; Spooner, A. F.; Stocking, William Alonzo, 1872-1926.; Thompson, F. H.; Tracy, Edward J.; Tuck, Charles Henry, 1881-1958.; Vincent, Edward F.; Warren, George F. (George Frederick), 1874-1938.; American Association of Creamery Butter Manufacturers.; American Institute of Cooperation.; Bank for Cooperatives.; Bureau of Raw Materials.; Committee for the Nation.; Cooperative Grange League Federation Exchange.; Dairymen's League Cooperative Association.; Farmers Milk Producers Association.; National Coopertive Milk Producers Federation.; National Council of Cooperative Associations.; National Council of Farmer Cooperatives.; National Dairy Union.; New York State College of Agriculture.; Southern Tariff Association.; Temple of Agriculture.; United States Chamber of Commerce.; United States Dairy Association.; United States International Trade Commission.; United States Tariff Commission.; United States. Armed Forces--Appropriations and expenditures.; United States. Agricultural Adjustment Administration.; United States. Farm Credit Administration.; United States. Federal Farm Board.; United States. Federal Reserve Board.; International Dairy Conference.; New England Agricultural Conference.
Titles:
American agriculturist.; Co-operative digest.
Subjects:
Agricultural credit--New York (State); Agricultural law and legislation--New York (State); Agriculture and politics.; Agriculture, Cooperative.; Antitrust law.; Banks and banking, Cooperative.; Cooperative societies--Denmark.; Dairy laws--New York (State); Dairying--Economic aspects.; Dairying, Cooperative--New York (State); Milk--Cooperative marketing.; Nitrate industry--Alabama--Muscle Schoals.; Politics, Practical--New York (State); Strikes and lockouts--United States.; Tariff--Law and legislation.; Taxation--Law and legislation--New York (State); Lawyers--United States.
Places:
United States--Economic policy.; United States--Politics and government--1913-1921.; United States--Politics and government--1919-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- National Council of Farmer Cooperatives, 1946 (Box 1)
- American Association of Creamery Butter Manufacturers (Box 1)
- Southern Tariff Association (Box 1)
- Pettengill (Box 1)
- Oleo Margarine Boycott, mainly corres. re Federal Trade Commission complaint agst. Wisconsin Cooperative Creamery Association, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
- Farms, Family Size (Box 1)
- McNary-Haugen Bill, 1928 (Box 1)
- Butter Tariff #2 (Box 1)
- Eastern States-Roscoe Sargent (Box 1)
- Holmes Case (Merle and George) (Box 1)
- Motor Vehicles-Automobiles (Box 1)
- National Dairy Union (Box 1)
- Keystone Cooperative Grape Association (Box 1)
- Richmond, Virginia-Farmers Milk Producers Association (Box 1)
- McKenzie, H.C.-Tariff Commission on Butter-Butter Tariff, Butter Imports (Box 1)
- National Cooperative Milk Producers Federation, 1944-1946 (Box 2)
- Federal Farm Board-Agriculture Marketing Act (Box 2)
- U.S. Chamber of Commerce (Box 2)
- American Institute of Cooperation (Box 2)
- Tariff Law of 1930 (Box 2)
- Cleveland (Box 2)
- Rural Credits (Box 2)
- Senator Blaine (Box 2)
- Industrial Conference Board (Box 2)
- Broome and Susquehanna Companies, 20 year Celebration, Oct. 24, 1936 (Box 2)
- Milk Bonding Law (Box 2)
- National Executive Committee Meetings (Box 2)
- Chesapeake and Ohio (Box 3)
- A.F. Spooner (Box 3)
- Fair Tariff League (Box 3)
- American Dairy Federation (Box 3)
- Washington Association (Box 3)
- Maryland and Virginia Milk Producers Association (Box 3)
- Western Tariff Association (Box 3)
- Egg Marketing, Pacific Coast (Box 3)
- National Dairy Council, M.D. Munn (Box 3)
- American Dairy Federation, Cooperative Institute Committee (Box 3)
- Minnesota Cooperative Creameries Association (Box 3)
- Muscle Shoals Nitrate (Box 3)
- Cornell University, NY State College of Agriculutre (Box 3)
- L.E. Griffing-Certified Milk (Box 3)
- California Cooperative Canneries (Box 3)
- Susquehanna County-Stevens Pt., Pennsylvania (Box 3)
- Federal Trade Commission (Box 3)
- Economic Conditions (Box 3)
- Muscle Shoals (Box 3)
- Plants of Association (Box 4)
- Consumers and Producers Organization Committee (Box 4)
- American Farm Bureau Association (Box 4)
- Cincinnati (Box 4)
- Briefs (Box 4)
- Political Platforms and Conventions; 1924, 1923, re Agriculture (Box 4)
- T.W. Phillips (Box 4)
- Tax Problem (Box 4)
- Chicago (Box 4)
- Plants of League Association (Box 4)
- National Council of Farmer Cooperatives (Box 4)
- National Council, Organization Survey (Box 4)
- USDA Pamphlets (Box 4)
- Cooperative Consumer Bulletin (Box 4)
- Bureau of Raw Materials (Box 4)
- New York Friut Growers (Box 5)
- Montgomery Ward (Box 5)
- National Association of Cooperatives (Box 5)
- Judges Appointed by Roosevelt (Box 5)
- Harrisburg Address (Box 5)
- Board of Directors, 1931 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Food Problem (Box 5)
- Federal Reserve System (Box 5)
- American Institute of Cooperation (Box 5)
- Legal Department (Box 5)
- Local Leagues (Box 5)
- American Agriculturalist (corresponded with Eastman), 1922-1924 (Box 5)
- World's Dairy Congress, 1928 (Box 5)
- World's Dairy Congress, 1923 (Box 5)
- Tariff Act, Casein (Box 5)
- Casein Tariff Hearing (Box 5)
- Casein Hearing (Box 5)
- Springville, Pennsylvania (Box 6)
- League of Nations - J.C.J. (Box 6)
- Legality of Cooperative Associations (Box 6)
- Southern States Cooperative (Box 6)
- Addresses and Writings (Box 6)
- Pennsylvania Legislature (Box 6)
- Certificates of Indebtedness (Box 6)
- National Board of Farm Organizations (Box 6)
- Addresses and Writings (Box 6)
- Writings and Addresses (Box 6)
- Reserves (Box 6)
- Barnes Case (Box 6)
- National Dairy Show (Box 6)
- Danish Cooperatives (Box 6)
- Philadelphia, Milk Producers Association (Box 6)
- USDA, 1918-1940 (Box 6)
- Levy Dairy Company (Box 7)
- Cooperative Pure Milk Association (Box 7)
- Vegetable Oils (Box 7)
- Pennsylvania Attorney (Box 7)
- New York State College of Agriculture, Correspondence with Prof. F.A. Harper (Box 7)
- National Association of Commissioners and Secretaries (Box 7)
- USDA Correspondence, 1941 on (Box 7)
- Voight Bill, 1923 (Box 7)
- Annual Meetings of D.L.C.A., Inc. (Box 7)
- Indictments, General (Box 7)
- Honesdale, Pennsylvania, 1923 (Box 7)
- Distributions, 1923 (Box 7)
- Auditing (Box 7)
- World's Dairy Congress Association (Box 7)
- Montrose, Pennsylvania, 1923 (Box 7)
- By Laws, 1923 (Box 7)
- N.M. Pr. Fed. Condensed Milk Committee, 1923 (Box 7)
- N.M. Federation, 1918-1924 (Box 7)
- Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture, 1923 (Box 8)
- N.C.M.P.F., 1926-1928; (Will be found after N.C.M.P.F., 1924 ) (Box 8)
- New Milford Milk and Cream Co., 1923 (Box 8)
- Starrucca, Pennsylvania, 1923 (Box 8)
- Holman, Charles W., 1927-1931 (Box 8)
- Chicago Milk Producers Marketing Co., 1923 (Box 8)
- National Council of Cooperative Associations, 1923 (Box 8)
- N.C.M. Prod. Fed., 1924 (Box 8)
- N.C.M. Prod. Fed. Annual Report; 1923, 1924, 1928 (Box 8)
- N.C.M. Prod. Fed. Annual Meeting, 1927-1928 (Box 8)
- Holman, 1925-1926 (Box 8)
- NCMPF Accounts, 1922-1925 (Box 8)
- Miller, J.D., Selling Contracts beginning with 1936 (Box 9)
- Bonds of Buyers, 1923 (Box 9)
- Trade Mark Sweden, 1923 (Box 9)
- Wisconsin Organization, 1923 (Box 9)
- Non-pooling Dairymens' Cooperative Association, 1923 (Box 9)
- Comparative Milk Prices (Box 9)
- Executive League Meeting Jan. 1936 (Box 9)
- Metropolitan Coop. Milk Prod. Bargaining Agency, Inc. (Box 9)
- Women-mobilizing in support of Coop. Market Movement, etc., 1934 (Box 9)
- J.D. Miller Grade A (Box 9)
- American Institute of Cooperation, General File, 1935 (Box 9)
- American Institute of Cooperation, General File, 1935 (Box 10)
- Wage and Hour Bill (Box 10)
- Farm Bill; Jones Bill and others (Box 10)
- Farm Bill; Jones Bill and others (Box 10)
- National Cooperative Council, 1938-1939 (Box 10)
- National Coopertaive Council Annual Meeting, 1938 (Box 10)
- J.D. Miller Article (Box 10)
- Pennsylvania State College, Miller Address (Box 11)
- National Coop. Council Annual Meeting, 1939 (Box 11)
- National Coop. Council Annual Meeting, 1939 (Box 11)
- Copies of "Our Food Problem" (Box 11)
- G.L.F. University, June 1939 (Box 11)
- Labor, 1939-1940 (Box 11)
- World Congress on Education for Democracy (Box 11)
- National Coop. Council General File, 1939-1940 (Box 12)
- Defense, National (Box 12)
- Farm Credit Admin. - General File beginning 1940 (Box 12)
- Farm Credit Admin. - transfer to Agric. Dept., first envelope (Box 12)
- National Coop. Council Annual Meeting, 1940 (Box 12)
- Farm Credit Admin., second envelope (Box 12)
- Agric. Advisory Council and Neutrality Act (Box 13)
- National Council of Farmers Coops., fifth envelope, 1945 (Box 13)
- National Council of Farmer Coops., fourth envelope, 1945 (Box 13)
- Omnibus Bill, 1941 (Box 13)
- Retirement Plan (Box 14)
- NCF Coops. General File, 1941 (Box 14)
- J.C.C., Bear Lake, Pennsylvania (Box 14)
- NCFC Annual Meeting, first envelope, 1941 (Box 14)
- Tax Reduction, Mellon Plan (Box 14)
- Political Conventions, 1940 (Box 14)
- NCFC General File, first envelope, 1941 (Box 14)
- NCFC Annual Meeting, 1942 (Box 14)
- Commodity Freezing Bull, 1941 (Box 14)
- NCFC General File, first envelope, 1942 (Box 14)
- Mid-summer Meeting, 1934 (Box 15)
- Supreme Court Decisions and Opinions (Box 15)
- Agricultural Census (Box 15)
- Bank for Cooperatives, first envelope, 1935-1938 (Box 15)
- New England Situation (Box 15)
- National Cooperative Council (Box 15)
- American Institute of Cooperation (Box 15)
- Bank for Cooperatives, second envelope, 1938-1941 (Box 15)
- Producers and Consumers Org. Committee (Box 16)
- Marketing Agreements (Box 16)
- Copies of Pooling Contracts, etc. (Box 16)
- Senator Wajtkowskie (Box 16)
- Withdrawal of NCMPF from Amer. Dairy Federation (Box 16)
- Milk Strikes, 1933 (Box 16)
- Lenroot-Taber Bill (Box 16)
- Copies of J.D. Miller Address (Box 16)
- Beaker Dairy Co. (Box 16)
- Buisness Men's Commission on Agriculture (Box 16)
- Robinson and Patman (Box 16)
- Federal Taxation, Social Security (Box 17)
- Dickerson Bill Pamphlets and Literature #2 (Box 17)
- Geyer, D.N. (Box 17)
- Atlantic City Meeting (Box 17)
- Address of J.D.M. on Supreme Court Issue (Box 17)
- Gold Clause (Box 17)
- Reorganization Bill (Box 17)
- Uniform Milk Ordinances (Box 17)
- Sub District Presidents (Box 18)
- Robinson Patman, first and fifth folders (Box 18)
- Dickerson Bill, first envelope (Box 18)
- Supreme Court Issue, first envelope, 1937 (Box 18)
- Statistics (Box 18)
- Associated Farmers (Box 18)
- Tugwell, Rexford G. (Box 18)
- Volume Differential (Box 18)
- Statistics on Special Subjects beginning 1941 (Box 18)
- J.D. Miller, Emergency Committee (Box 18)
- Amer. Inst. of Cooperation, 1932-1934 (Box 18)
- Committee for the Nation Corresp., Edward A. Rumely (Box 19)
- Budget Allotment Bill (Box 19)
- NCMPF Annual Meeting, 1932 (Box 19)
- Floods (Box 19)
- Agricultural Adjustment Administration (Box 19)
- National Cooperative Council, 1933-1935 (Box 19)
- Legal Papers (Box 19)
- New Orleans Indictment (Box 19)
- Bonding Act, New York (Box 19)
- Donnely Act and Amendments (Box 19)
- Pennsylvania Forms (Box 19)
- New Jersey Bank Acct. (Box 19)
- U.S. Food Admin., Federal Milk Commission (Box 19)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 20)
- Mac Dermott, D.C., General File (Box 20)
- State of Wisconsin (Box 20)
- Temple of Agriculture (Box 20)
- Anti-trust Laws (Box 20)
- Cost of Milk Production, first folder (Box 20)
- Filled Milk, Enforcement (Box 20)
- Dairy Marketing Committee (Box 20)
- National Board of Farm Organizations (Box 20)
- Tariffs (Box 20)
- Cost of Milk Production, second folder (Box 20)
- Miscellaneous A (Box 21)
- Miscellaneous B (Box 21)
- Cost of Milk Production, first folder (Box 21)
- Contracts (Box 21)
- Contracts with Dealers (Box 21)
- Finances (Box 21)
- McFadden Credit Bill (Box 21)
- J.D.Miller, Transportation (Box 21)
- Copies of Addresses (Box 22)
- Transportation Committee (Box 22)
- Sullivan and Cromwell Mortgaging (Box 22)
- Motor Trucking (Box 22)
- Copies of Addresses (Box 22)
- Reports of Committees to U.S. Chamber of Commerce (Box 22)
- Edward J. Tracy (Box 22)
- English Munitions Case (Box 22)
- Gray and Co. (Box 22)
- Scranton Coop. (Box 22)
- Susquehanna County, Pa. (Box 22)
- Washington (Box 23)
- Senator Strauss, 1923 (Box 23)
- Agricultural Conference, Jan. 1942 (Box 23)
- American Dairy Federation (Box 23)
- National Cooperative Council D (Box 23)
- National Cooperative Council B (Box 23)
- Farm Credit Admin. (Box 23)
- Federal Tariff Commission, Casein Case (Box 23)
- New Milford Local (Box 23)
- Grain Corporation (Box 23)
- National Coop. Council (Box 23)
- Northeast Agricultural Conference (Box 23)
- Newspaper Clippings, three envelopes (Box 24)
- Copies of "Our Food Problem," and Address by J.D. Miller (Box 24)
- National Council Bulletin (Box 24)
- J.D.M. Address and Price Fixing Letters (Box 24)
- Tax on Cooperatives (Box 24)
- J.D. Miller, Two Addresses, 1939 (Box 25)
- Political Conventions, 1939 (Box 25)
- NCMPF, 1940-1943 (Box 25)
- NCMPF, 1930-1934 (Box 25)
- American Bar Association, 1930 (Box 25)
- Closing of Plants (Box 26)
- New Milford Local, 1930 (Box 26)
- NCMPF, minutes, letters, etc. (Box 26)
- Reed, Stanley (Box 26)
- Holman, Committee on Investigation (Box 26)
- World's Dairy Congress, Booklets, etc. (Box 26)
- Uniform Cooperative Laws, 1930-1931 (Box 26)
- Uniform Cooperative Marketing Law, 1934-1935 (Box 26)
- Edward F. Vincent, 1923 (Box 26)
- C.O. Moser, Amer. Cotton Coop. Assn. (Box 26)
- Farm Board Mortgage (Box 26)
- Richmond Coop. Milk Prod. Assn. (Box 26)
- Oregon Coop. Council (Box 26)
- Sud-district Organizations (Box 26)
- J.D. Miller, Land Banks (Box 26)
- St. Louis, 1931 (Box 26)
- Duties of Directors and Sub-district Presidents (Box 27)
- Agric. Adjustment Act, Agric. Adjust. Admin, NIRA, etc. (Box 27)
- Price Fixing, Misc. (Box 27)
- Price Fixing, General and Misc. (Box 27)
- Price Fixing, Specific Addresses by J.D. Miller (Box 27)
- Copies of "Our Food Program," addresses by J.D. Miller (Box 27)
- American Council Agr. (Box 28)
- American Institute of Cooperation (Box 28)
- NCMPF, 1946 (Box 28)
- Farm Credit Admin. (Box 28)
- Commodity Exchange Admin. (Box 28)
- Tariff, 1929-1930 (Box 28)
- Curtis-Crisp Bill (Box 28)
- Loan Agreement, 1940 (Box 28)
- Burley Tobacco Growers Coop. Assn. (Box 28)
- International Wheat Pool Conference Committee (Box 28)
- Kansas Coop. Wheat Marketing Assn. (Box 28)
- Copies of "Our Food Program" (Box 28)
- Guernsey Differential (Box 28)
- Farm Relief Fill, 1929 (Box 28)